# **Ethan McDowell**

# Web Developer

Address Detroit, MI, 48209

**Phone** (313) 400-5611

E-mail ethan.r.mcdowell@gmail.com

Ambitious web developer brings enthusiasm and detailed understanding of various programming languages to webpage planning, development and maintenance. Experience designing and developing sites from concept to roll out. Foundational grasp of various CSS, HTML, and JavaScript options, plugins, development platforms and security requirements according to up-to-date standards.

#### Skills

HTML/CSS	
Wordpress	
JavaScript	
Social Media Marketing	
Web Design	
APIs	

## **Work History**

2018-08 - Current

# Web Developer

Street Beet, Detroit, MI

- Employed coding practices based on commonly accepted standards to establish site layout and user interface.
- Conducted testing and review of website design for responsiveness, clarity and effectiveness.
- Collaborated with restaurant owners to determine organizational need, designing pages to meet demand.

2017-09 - Current

#### **Bartender**

Checker Bar, Detroit, MI

- Maintained secure cash drawers, promptly resolving discrepancies for accuracy.
- Applied excellent organizational and multitasking abilities to handle simultaneous customer, team and business needs while avoiding unnecessary

delays or errors.

• Kept accurate inventories and notified management of ordering needs for liquor, beer, wine and bar supplies.

#### 2011-10 - 2017-07

### **Practice Manager**

Mohawk Village Medical, New York, NY

- Ordered all office supplies and kept check on inventory levels.
- Oversaw fiscal operations, including accounting, budgeting, authorizing expenditures and financial reporting.
- Properly calibrated and adjusted malfunctioning equipment to achieve precise test results.
- Conducted preliminary evaluations, including measuring weight, temperature and blood pressure, and documented results with accuracy.

## **Education**

2020-09 - Current Certification: Full-Stack Web Development

Michigan State University - Detroit, MI

2006-01 - 2010-05 Bachelor of Science: Medical Laboratory Science

University Of New Hampshire - Durham, NH